

Ndifreke Okorie

+358-468955815 Andi7@yahoo.co.uk https://github/packetech

in Ndifreke Okorie

Proactive, with over two decades professional ICT, AI, ML, big data analytics and self-taught software developer with a passion for problem solving. Specializes in full-stack development, solution architecture, project management, JavaScript, data analytics/Python and other web tech stack. Recognised for leadership abilities, teamwork and project delivery.

Professional Experience

Bouygues Construction

Apr 2013 - June 2021

IT Manager Abuja, NG

IT Infrastructure Management and Project Leadership (Nigeria)

- Deployed and decommissioned IT infrastructure across 4 new construction project sites, while simultaneously managing IT operations for 6 existing sites using IT staff and outsourced contractors to meet operational timelines
- Directed the successful relocation of the head office IT data center to a new location, with all it's legacy connectivities and firewalls

Cotecna Dec 2008 - Mar 2013

Assistant IT Manager Abuja, NG

IT Infrastructure manager (Northern Nigeria)

Setup the VSAT ground station, backend application servers (including Windows/Linux, MS Exchange, DNS, DHCP, AD, WSUS, Firewall, Routers) and the network of the company's valuation and classification center (VCC) in Abuja using HP G4 servers and Cisco devices for smooth trade facilitations.

Projects

Fruit Shop

https://ndibuilt-full-stack-ecommerce.netlify.app

- Developed a full stack ecommerce fruit shop app using NextJS and TailwindCSS for an effective online sales and UX
- Integrated Zustand for global state management of the app components
- Incorporated Stripe billing via API and Key Secret for users payment and backend transaction management

Hulknormous (Fitness App)

https://ndibuilt-fitness.netlify.app

- Designed an intelligent workout web app using ReactJS and TailwindCSS for personalized body training plans
- Creating a rule-based algorithm for smart workouts taking care of all experience levels and difficulties

Todo App

https://ndibuilt-todo.netlify.app

- Built a responsive todo app using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to enable users maintain a list of important todos
- Used device browser local storage to persist entries, so CRUD activities can be effectively carried out

Al Chatbot

https://github.com/packetech/Coding_Journey/tree/main/THE-COMPLETE-JAVASCRIPT-COURSE/Projects/AI_chatbot

- Created a command line AI chatbot using JavaScript, to act as a quick and simple knowledge base enabling users ask for any information and get appropriate answers
- Incorporated Eden AI apiKey authentication to use Eden API
- Included an async function to take care of network delays

Education

Arcada University of Applied Sciences

Aug 2021 - Aug 2022

Master of Engineering, Big Data Analytics

Helsinki, Fl

Demonstrated expertise in software development and resampling techniques

Nasarawa State University

Nov 2020 - pending

Master of Science in Computer Sciences (Software Engineering Concentration)

Keffi, NG

Demonstrated expertise in data structure and algorithm best practices

University of Texas

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

PG program, AI and Machine Learning

Austin TX, USA

Demonstrated expertise in deep learning, computer vision and NLP

University of Calabar

Oct 1990 - Jun 1995

B.Sc. (hons) in Physics

Calabar, NG

Demonstrated expertise in astrophysics, geophysics and computer programming

Skills

JavaScript ReactJS, NextJS, SvelteKit, Qwik, Node.js, Express.js

Python Data analytics, visual analytics, AI & ML, Django, Flask (sample face recognition & other codes are on github)

Web HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, Firebase, GIT, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, GCP (sample projects are on github)

Database NoSQL, SQL, PostgreSQL, Mongo.db

Design Canva, Figma, Storyboard, PixIr, Photoshop, Coreldraw (for UI/UX, wireframe, etc.)